Guide to the Barbara Howes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1922-1995; Series II; 5; (5 boxes)
  - Literary correspondence (Box 16)
    One folder of miscellaneous correspondence, including letters from James Laughlin, Frederick Morgan, Robert Wilson, Harriet Woods, Frank MacShane, plus copies of Howes' letters.
  - Hambleton, Merrell (Box 16)
  - Schaffner Agency (Box 16)
  - Literary business correspondence (Box 16)
  - Pittsburgh University Press (Box 16)
  - Literary business and personal correspondence, 4 (Box 16)
  - Gioia, Dana (Box 16)
  - Associated Writing Programs (Box 16)
  - Political correspondence (Box 16)
  - MacInnes, Colin: letter regarding Ada Levenson, undated (Box 16)
  - Gress, Elsa: letters and copies of her stories, undated (Box 16)
    Also contains letters from Arabel Porter and Philip Rahv
  - Brandeis University Creative Arts Awards, correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 16)
  - Literary correspondence, undated (Box 16)
    Includes correspondence from Clay Head (husband of poet Eunice Tietjens), Thekla Clark, Jane Sabersky, Milton Saul, Harry Rago, Elsa Gress, Manny Weisbuch, Robert Allen, Warner Mendel, Ned O'Gorman (with review of "Light and Dark"), Harriet Allen, Aida Anny Chatarain Corardiere, Margaret Marshall, Emory Neff, Mary Britton Miller (Isabel Bolton), Lee Anderson, Nona Balakian, Marion Strobel.
  - Academy of American Poets, correspondence from Elizabeth Kray, undated (Box 16)
  - "Literary Curiosities," acrostic poem on Barbara owes by Bernard Winebaum and fan letter from India, undated (Box 16)
  - Family correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 16)
    One folder of correspondence from Barbara Howes' mother, her former governess, "Cumsie" (sp?), and of her governess, Vera Foster.
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, correspondence, 1955 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with publishers (Box 16)
  - "Collection of stories," detailed literary criticism from Robert Wilson, Dana Gioia, Charlee and Richard Wilbur, etc., undated (Box 16)
  - ''Miscellaneous items of interest" (Box 16)
    One folder of miscellany: long letter from Milton Saul, clippings and programs from Eranos conferences, copy of a letter from Adrienne Rich, etc.
  - "Reassignment of Copyright," correspondence, undated (Box 16)
  - Cook, Helen Cummings, with articles by her and corrections by Barbara Howes, undated (Box 16)
  - Cunard, Crystal: copies of letters by "Cunard" to various newspapers, undated (Box 16)
  - Wilbur, Charlee, 1960-1961 (Box 16)
    Letters from Charlee Wilbur (Mrs. Richard Wilbur) from 1960-61, plus one poem by C. W., detailing much background of Wilbur's activities.
  - de Angulo, Ximena, 1946-1947 (Box 16)
  - Political correspondence, undated (Box 16)
    Includes correspondence from Barbara Jordan, Madeleine Kumin, Edmund Muskie, Eugene McCarthy, Edward Kennedy, Joseph D. Tydings, George Aiken, plus copies of Howes' letters to Bill Maudlin.
  - "Responses to book & card for Cary," correspondence (Box 16)
  - "Letters - impersonal, non-literary," correspondence (Box 16)
  - Literary business correspondence, undated; 2 (Box 16)
    Literary correspondence from David Clark, William Jay Smith, George Garrett, Howard Moss, Malcolm Bradbury, Howard Nemerov, Nan Talese, Joseph Langland, Arthur Luce Klein, Norman Holmes Pearson, Gene Baro, Edward Weeks, David Posner, Louis Untermeyer, Louis Martz, Richard Eberhart, Leah Bodine Drake, John Sargeant, Roger Stallman, Florence Baker Lennan, Lee Anderson, John Holmes, Constance Carrier, Norman T. di Giovanni, Angel Flores, Kit Forster, Margaret Marshall, Edouard Roditi, Jacques Barzun, Leonie Adams, Harold Vinal, Seymour Lawrence, Jackson Matthews, Allen Tate, etc.
    Setting copies: manuscript copies of "Early Supper," "Galveston Beach," "The Gallery," and "Mistral".
  - Postcards and Christmas cards, undated; 2 (Box 17)
    Includes cards from: Barbara Maniha (cousin), Marjorie Saul, Robert Shaw (letter), Lewis Turco (letter), James Merrill, Charlee Wilbur, Stephen Sandy, Donald Hall, Ben Belitt, Robert Wilson, Marshall Clements, Denise Levertov, John Frederick Nims, Robert Shaw, Philip Hoff (Governor of Vermont), Jacques Barzun, Susan Hurley, Harry Duncan, Warner Mendel, Franco Pasquati, Sam Hunter, Kit Foster, Ximena de Angulo, Toto von Koopmann, Harold Acton, Nicky Mariano, Olga Frobe-Capteyn, Lucy Heyer, Tony Clark, Allanah Harper, Manny Weisbuch, Ned O'Gorman, Marjorie Ferguson, Orrea Pernel, Robert Stange, Isabelle Gardner
  - Dinesen, Isak: correspondence by and about, undated; 2 (Box 17)
    This folder includes telegram from Isak Dinesen to William Jay Smith, letter from Isak Dinesen to William Jay Smith, note from Clara Selborn, secretary and companion to Dinesen, copies of Howes' letters to Clara Selborn, Isak Dinesen and Birthe Arnbak (Danish poet and protege of Dinesen), notes by William Jay Smith about his introduction of Dinesen at the Poetry Center in NYC, draft of William Jay Smith's review of "Anecdotes of Destiny" with corrections, note from Robert Evitt, literary editor of the New Republic, copy of Barbara Howes poem about visiting Dinesen, letter from Parmenia Migel Ekstrom (Dinesen biographer), Clippings, reviews of Isak Dinesen (including William Jay Smith), article by Barbara Howes, Letter (carbon) to Miss Svendsen (Clara Selborn) about her appearance at the Poetry Center, Four letters from Birthe Arnbak, including a statement by Dinesen about Howes' poems and a copy of Dinesen's letter (in Swedish), Letter from Clara Selborn, correspondence from Clara Selborn, correspondence from bookseller Robert Wilson about Dinesen bibliography.
  - "Fresh-air Fund Children," correspondence (Box 17)
  - Spark, Muriel (Box 17)
  - Smith, William Jay (Box 17)
  - Correspondence related to the eviction of Welland Lathrop, circa 1947 (Box 17)
  - Drafts of outgoing letters (Box 17)
  - Original poems, cards and notes, 4 (Box 17)
    Includes cards/poems from Rene Char ("Chanson des Etage" 1/30 numbered and inscribed to Howes), Richard Wilbur, William Meredith, John Holmes, Theodore Roethke, Gertrude Stein, Charles Olson (inscribed to Caresse Crosby), Guillaume Apollinaire, Winfield T. Scott, Ruthven Todd, Richard Wilbur, William Carlos Williams, James Merrill, William and Manka Dudley, Malcolm Cowley, Elsa Gress and Clifford, A. J. Seymour, Anthony Harrigan, Jean Garrigue, Margaret and Richard Archer, John Ciardi, Serena Broughton, Dudley Fitts, Eudora Welty, Stephen Spender, John Fuller, Claude Fredericks, James Broughton and Susana Hunt, Robert Francis, William Stafford, Gunther Eich, Gil Williams, Richard Wilbur and William Jay Smith, Robert Phillips, Boris and Anne Bittker, Lewis Turco, Carl Dennis, Joseph Langland, Leslie Fiedier, Marty and Jack Hall, Anthony Ostroff, Ishmael Reed, Peter Viereck, Daniel Hoffman, James Laughlin, Peter Blume, Robert Penn "Red'' Warren, Granville Hicks, Helen and Bill Vanderbilt, Alain de la Cotardiere, Robert Fitzgerald, Kathleen MacArthur, Helen and Allen Tate, Joseph Cary, A. R. Ammons, Teo Savory, Alastair Reid, Daniel Halpern, Clara Svendsen plus William Jay Smith's article in the New York Times, poems for wedding of Smith's stepson on 12/11/76.
  - Correspondence, 1952, 1973 (Box 17)
    Includes correspondence from Howes to her mother, Olga and Lucy Heyer, Cary F. Baynes, notes from Adlai Stevenson.
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 17)
    Includes postcards from Dore Ashton, Donald Hall, Wallace Fowlie, Bill and Leonie Adams, Louise Bogan, Seamus Heaney, Katharine Anne Porter, W. H. Auden, Eudora Welty and Tennessee Williams.
  - Announcement cards, undated (Box 17)
  - Literary correspondence (Box 17)
    Includes correspondence from Les Phillabaum, John Williams, James Trissell (broadsides of American poetry), Dore Ashton, Joseph Cary, H. L. Mitchell, Charlee Wilbur, Elsa Gress, Charles Guenther, Ximena de Angulo, Greg Kuzma, Manny Weisbuch, Ned O'Gorman, Miller Williams, John Rees Moore, John Frederick Nims, Emily Grosholz, Francis Coleman Rosenberger, Lysander Kemp, Honora Gifford, Norman Thomas di Giovanni, Beatrice Roethke, Eduoard Roditi, Robert Wilson, Bradford Morrow, Galen Williams, plus copies of Howes' letters to Charlee and Richard Wilbur, William Maxwell and others, also included in Richard Wilbur's review of Howes' "In the Cold Country".
  - Postcards (Box 17)
    Includes postcards from Ximena de Angulo, Nancy and Bill Konnick, Frank MacShane, Sonja Smith, Nicky Mariano, Marty and Jack Hall, Andrew Imbrie (composer), Harry and Peggy Craig, Myra and Jack Sweeney, Jean and Dudley Bahlman, Shirley Komrower, Paul Mellon, Dudley and Anne Hartt (cousin), Elsa Hauschka, Kathleen MacArthur, Norman Holmes Pearson, Helen Vanderbilt, Thekla Clark, Paul Feeley.
  - Family correspondence, undated (Box 17)
    Includes handwritten letters from Howes to her mother describing her first trip abroad; plus four letters from William Jay Smith written when Howes worked for Southern Tenant Farmers' Union.
  - Literary ephemera and correspondence (Box 17)
    Includes a broadside by Magloire Saint-Aude inscribed to Howes and William Jay Smith, two Rollie McKenna photos of Howes, birthday telegram from William Jay Smith, reading announcement, newspaper articles about Howes by William Jay Smith, announcement of Wesleyan Poetry Series with Howes books as one of last four published, two letters from the President of Bennington College to Howes, 1936, inscribed poetry offprint from Robert Francis, miscellaneous typescripts (by Peter Viereck, Ned O'Gorman, etc) inscribed to Howes, article manuscript by Howes about little magazines, poems from Light and Dark
  - "Early Literary Business," literary correspondence and setting copy of "Ode to Poseidon," "Flight," and "A Rune for C.", 2 (Box 17)
    Includes correspondence from Daniel Halpern, Donald Gallup, Galen Williams, Jon Silkin, Philip Hoff, Mark Strand, Frank MacShane, George Garrett, plus various editors.
  - Literary correspondence, undated (Box 18)
    Includes broadsides and poetry manuscripts.
    Includes correspondence from: Oskar Kokoschka; Edouard Roditi; Barbara Howes broadside with notes on verso; Richard Wilbur, xeroxes of Richard Wilbur's "Cierihews for David'' (Smith); one A4 notepad with typed poems, autograph manuscript poems, notes for poems by Howes
  - Literary correspondence (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Richard Wilbur, Hardie St. Martin, Robert Phillips, Helen Vanderbilt, Robert Shaw, Dana Gioia, Marshall Clements, Fred Chappell, Joseph Cary, plus retained copies of Howes' replies.
  - Literary correspondence (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Eleanor Clark, plus clippings, list of reviews, list of books and awards, etc.
  - Literary correspondence, 1972-1989 (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Glyn Collins, Robert Phillips, Clifford Wright, Josephine Jacobsen, John Crews, Malcolm and Muriel Cowley, Florette Morand, Alfred Corn, Ned O'Gorman, Robert Wilson, Judith Wright, William Jay Smith, Robert Shaw, Charles Guenther, Milton Saul, Edouard Roditi, Jacques Barzun, Barbara Howes, William Jay Smith.
  - Literary correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Marshall Clements, William Jay Smith, Robert Wilson, Helen Vanderbilt, Fred Chappell.
  - Wilson, Robert: copies of letters from literary people sold to bookseller Robert Wilson in 1985 (Box 18)
  - Braithwaite, Edward Kamau: correspondence and a pamphlet by him inscribed to Howes, undated (Box 18)
    Includes three sets of Barbara Howes' poetry (clean typescript copies) with Italian translations.
  - "Eva -Extra Copies of Letters" Political correspondence (Box 18)
    Letters from Barbara Howes about Genoveva Forest de Sastre, a political prisoner in Spain (and subject of one of Howes' poems).
  - "Green Diamond Plots and Plans," correspondence regarding the dedication of Mildred C. Howes' Demonstration Forest, undated (Box 18)
  - Financial correspondence (Box 18)
  - Kaplan, Peter: literary correspondence regarding poetry and small presses, undated (Box 18)
  - "Institute Affair/ NBA Affair 78," National Book Award ceremonies correspondence, programs etc., 1978 (Box 18)
  - Political correspondence, 1970s (Box 18)
  - Literary correspondence, 1971- (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Louis Untermeyer, Norman Holmes Pearson, Robert Wilson, Edward Kamau Braithwaite, Harry Taylor (author of "An Afternoon of Pocket Billiards"), Frank MacShane, Daniel Halpern, Miller Williams, V. S. Reid, Gil Williams, James Vinson, Lewis Turco, Merloyd Lawrence (wife of Seymour Lawrence), plus correspondence about the Christopher Award for Eye of the Heart.
  - Literary correspondence, undated (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Lionel Trilling, John Crowe Ransom, Brewster Ghiselin, Delmore Schwartz, Oscar Williams, Philip Rahv, Allen Tate.
  - Acceptances, with notes from Dwight MacDonald, Harold Vinal, 1940-1941 (Box 18)
  - Rejection notices, with notes from John Crowe Ransom, Klaus Mann, Selden Rodman, James Laughlin, 1939-1941 (Box 18)
  - "Genoveva F. Forest," correspondence and other materials, undated; 3 (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Katharine Graham, Barbara Probst Solomon, Hubert Humphrey, Ted Kennedy, Edmund Muskie, Gary Hart, Joseph Biden, Nona Balakian, Richard Wilbur.
  - Literary correspondence, 2 (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Josephine Jacobsen, Dare Ashton, Denise Levertov, Jacques Barzun, Kathleen MacArthur, Julia Randall, Donald Hall, Richard and Charlee Wilbur, Charlee Wilbur, Stephen Sandy, William Jay Smith (& Sonja), Robert Wilson, Ximena de Angulo, Charles Guenther, Birthe Arnbak, Patrick Leahy, Robert Phillips, Frank MacShane, Frank Glazer, Ann Waldron, Milton Saul, Alfred Corn, Louise Bogan, Philip Hoff, Bill and Hilary Rodham Clinton, Beatrice Roethke, Stephen Uvingston, plus copies of several Howes Christmas poems, including "Myself" (1991), "Older" (1990) and "Quilt of an Old Pattern" (1988).
  - Correspondence (Box 18)
    Includes correspondence from Paul Carman, Josephine Jacobsen, William Jay Smith, Kathleen MacArthur, Helen Vanderbilt, Ned O'Gorman, Robert Wilson, Muriel Cowley.
  - "Odds and Ends," assorted sheets and clippings about friends, undated (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, retained copies of outgoing letters, undated (Box 18)
  - Announcements, 1947-1983; 3 (Box 19)
    Includes announcement cards for the following books "A Private Signal" (1977), "Moving" (1983), plus copies of the announcement for the marriage of Barbara Howes and William Jay Smith (10/1/47), a reading/exhibit at the American Library, Florence, Italy (undated), Barbara Howes' 70th Birthday, "A Constancy of Cousins" family reunion (undated).
  - Political and editorial correpsondence, retained copies, 1977-1978 (Box 19)
  - "Replies to Blast II," political correspondence, 1971 (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from John V. Lindsay, Anthony Lewis, Tom Braden, Herbert Mittgang, Robert A Dahl, Edmund Muskie, Paul N. McCloskey, Thomas F. Eagleton, Frank E. Moss, Jonathan Bingham, Harriet Eisman, Sidney R. Yates, William B. Saxbe, Jack Moskowitz, George Palmer, William Proxmire, Robert F. Drinan, Alan Cranston, Jacob K. Javtts, Clifford P. Case, Lawrence F. O'Brien, Vance Hartke, Tom Wicker, Charles E. Goodell, Robert T. Stafford, Hans J. Morgenthau, Mrs. T. Moll Shaw, James Reston, Edward M. Kennedy, Charles H. Percy, E. Anzaldua, Watler F. Mondale, Winston Prouty, Birch Bayh, Robert T. Stafford, George D. Aiken, Gilbert A. Harrison.
  - "Bennington College: News and Rows" correspondence from Howes to Merrell Hambleton at Bennington, 1975-1979 (Box 19)
  - Literary correspondence, 1974-1993 (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from Daniel Halpern, William Jay Smtth, Josephine Jacobsen, Willard Cook, Shirley Komrower, plus a stray royalty statement from 1993.
  - Reviews of Howes' books and literary correspondence (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from John Hall Wheelock, Katharine Anne Porter (copy).
  - Wilson, Robert. Phoenix Bookshop, correspondence and list of books sold to him, 1965-1982 (Box 19)
  - "Louise Bogan Enterprise," correspondence and typescripts, 1971-1975 (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from William Maxwell, Elizabeth Frank, Ruth Ummer, plus copies of Howes' letters.
  - Literary business, correspondence and papers, 1977-1984 (Box 19)
    One large folder of editor/publisher correspondence, stray literary correspondence, and miscellaneous literary papers (permissions, contracts, financial statements, etc.)
    Includes correspondence from Dana Gioia, Ben Lewis, William Page, Robert Holladay, Paul B. Janeczko, William Jay Smith, Brad Morrow, Kathy Walkup, Frederick Morgan, Tom Dodge, Samuel Hazo.
  - "Doctoral Reply to Beaver Country Day," copies of a letter by Howes, plus copies of a Jungian questionnaire addressed to poets, 1981 (Box 19)
  - "Little Blue Book," literary correspondence, 1979 (Box 19)
    Includes letters from Dan Gioia, Robert Wilson, Peter Alden Brazeau, Edouard Roditi, Mitton Saul.
  - Literary correspondence: "Responses to Hollins Critic piece on me, etc.", 1978 (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from Frank MacShane, Robert Phillips, Fred Chappell, Charles Guenther, Kim Cushman, Milton Saul.
  - Correspondence, retained copies, 1976-1977 (Box 19)
  - Wright, Judith, 1960-1966 (Box 19)
    Also contains correspondence from Louis Untermeyer and Peter Davison, plus a photograph of Wright and [daughter?] Meredith, plus holograph notes/poems by Howes.
  - "Possible Readings, Lectures, Business," literary and business correspondence about poetry readings (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from George [___?], Donald Gallup, Ned O'Gorman, Frank MacShane, Edwin Honig, William Stafford, Roy Basler, Victor Howes, Melvin B. Yoken, Richard M. Hartt, Holly Stevens, Arthur Carr, Joseph Langland, Sara deFord, Elliot Coleman, Fred Chappell, Stanton Hoffman.
  - "Anthologies using poems," Literary correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from Mark Strand, Laura Chester, plus anthology lists
  - "Letters, people interested in work" Literary correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from Muriel Cowley, Fred Chappell, Karla [___?], John Norbutt Marshall Clements, Jay Barwell.
  - "Mitch: material and recent plans", undated (Box 19)
    One folder of correspondence and articles about H. L. Mitchell and the Southern Tenant Farmer's Union.
  - Literary correspondence, undated (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from Donald Hall, Matti Meged, Frank MacShane, Mary Jane Moffat, Robert Phillips.
  - Political correspondence, undated (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from George J. Mitchell, Patrick Leahy, Charlee Wilbur, James M. Jeffords.
  - "Campaign '82: letters, publicity releases, copies of responses, etc." Political correspondence, 1982 (Box 19)
    Includes correspondence from: Robert T. Stafford, Paul Warnke, Ted Kulongoski, Rodger McDaniel.
  - Wilson, Robert. Phoenix Bookshop, correspondence, lists of books, and appraisal material, 1965-1981 (Box 19)
  - "Various Who's Who editions" business correspondence with Who's Who about bio listing, undated (Box 19)
  - "Letters to Charlee Wilbur," letters from Howes to Charlee Wilbur, written in the 1950s when Howes was living in Italy, 1955-1956 (Box 19)
- Personal and Financial Papers, 1914-1995; Series III; 6.25; (7 boxes)
  Personal papers relating to Howes and her family, particularly her sons David and Gregory Smith; lists and notes related to her publications and awards; financial and tax records; and printed ephemera.
  - Grade school scrapbook, [1920s] (Box 20)
  - Royalty statements, 1990 (Box 20)
  - Lists of books and awards; biographical notes, undated (Box 20)
  - Phoenix Bookshop catalogs, undated (Box 20)
  - Blank book, undated (Box 20)
  - Tax returns, 1988 (Box 20)
  - Southern Tenant Farmers' Union, business and organization materials, undated (Box 20)
  - "Things of Interest - History, Current events," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 20)
  - "Clark Art Institute," New York Times, newspaper clipping, 1975 May 21 (Box 20)
    New York Times article on the Clark Art Institute's 20th Anniversary Show with photo of Eugene Boudin painting, which was bequeathed to the Institute in 1973 by Mildred Cox Howes, mother of Barbara Howes.
  - "David Smith", [1980]; 10 (Box 20)
    Materials about son David Smith: scholarship - Columbia, New Paltz; hospitalization; letters from Barbara Howes and William Jay Smith; current Last Will and Testament (1960); separate file about arrest in Austria and consequences.
  - Tax records, 1986-1990 (Box 20)
  - Financial records, undated (Box 20)
  - Insurance records, 1988-1989 (Box 20)
  - Southern Tenant Farmers' Union: correspondence with H. R. Mitchell, undated (Box 20)
  - Newspaper clippings about Kim Cushman, undated (Box 20)
  - Financial records, [1960-1900?]; 8 (Box 20)
  - Tax records, 1989-1990 (Box 20)
  - Medical records, undated; 2 (Box 20)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated; 2 (Box 20)
  - Gregory Smith, undated (Box 20)
  - Garden plans, undated (Box 20)
  - Tax records, 1986 (Box 20)
  - Financial and personal records, [1960-1990?]; 4 (Box 20)
  - Legal records, undated; 2 (Box 21)
    One large folder of correspondence with lawyer John H. Williams of Bennington concerning financial affairs and arrangements for David, plus letters from him and correspondence with Manny Weisbuch, Howes' financial advisor.
  - Engagement calendars, 1960-1989; 26 (Box 21)
  - "Gregory Smith", undated; 4 (Box 22)
  - Latin American Literature, articles, undated (Box 22)
  - Unsorted material, undated (Box 22)
  - Newspaper clippings and tearsheets, undated (Box 22)
  - "Blast III, articles and notes" typescript and newspaper clippings, undated (Box 22)
  - Catalogues, addresses & guarantees, undated (Box 22)
  - "Things of Interest - idiocies, nonsense," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 22)
  - "Things of Interest - Nature," newspaper clippings, [1960s?] (Box 22)
  - "Things of Interest - magic and mythology," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 22)
  - "Things of Interest - UFOs," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 22)
  - "Things of Interest," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 22)
  - "About Auden," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 22)
  - "Things of Interest - writers," newspaper clippings, undated (Box 22)
  - "Book reviews of interest," newspaper clippings and tearsheets, undated (Box 22)
  - Bennington College, 1932-37, 1937 (Box 22)
  - Books relating to Africa, 1960s-1980s; 7 (Box 22)
  - "David Smith," letters, school records, and psychiatric correspondence, 1960-1980; 8 (Box 22)
  - "Gregory Smith," school records, 1955-1970; 3 (Box 22)
  - Recipes, undated (Box 22)
  - Garden plans and information, undated (Box 22)
  - Financial and tax records, including will, undated; 4 (Box 23)
  - Records relating to the care of Howes' house in Pownal, Vermont, circa 1965-1990 (Box 23)
  - Psychiatric and marriage counseling notes, 1960s (Box 23)
  - Medical records, 1960s (Box 23)
  - Bennington College diploma, 1937 (Box 23)
  - Newspaper clippings, undated; 2 (Box 23)
  - Drawings by Greg Smith and others, undated (Box 23)
  - Notes on Eranos conference and an article by Joseph Campbell, undated (Box 23)
  - Newspaper clippings and records about Pownal, Vermont, circa 1950-1990; 2 (Box 23)
  - National Institute of Arts & Letters, copy of an "Award in Literature" letter from William Maxwell (citation) and program of ceremony, 1971 (Box 23)
  - "Turtle," drawing by David Smith, undated (Box 23)
  - Wesleyan University Spring Poetry Festival booklet, 1960 (Box 23)
  - The Williams Record, (Williams College) regarding a reading by Howes and Richard Wilbur, 1959 (Box 23)
  - "In Memory of Robert Frost," copy of program for memorial at Amherst College, 1963 February 17 (Box 23)